<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<researcher>
	<name>Nuno Laranjeiro</name>
	<citations>
		<total>340</total>

		<numberOfCitations year="2010">30</numberOfCitations>
		<numberOfCitations year="2011">35</numberOfCitations>
		<numberOfCitations year="2012">52</numberOfCitations>
		<numberOfCitations year="2013">56</numberOfCitations>
		<numberOfCitations year="2014">51</numberOfCitations>
		<numberOfCitations year="2015">48</numberOfCitations>
		
	</citations>
	
	<publications>		
	
		<publication>
			<title>Robustness-Driven Resilience Evaluation of Self-Adaptive Software Systems</title>
			<author>Javier Cámara</author>
			<author>Rogério de Lemos</author>
			<author>Nuno Laranjeiro</author>
			<author>Rafael Ventura</author>
			<author>Marco Vieira</author>
			<date>2015/5/4</date>
			<additionalInformation>	</additionalInformation>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<description>
				Abstract—An increasingly important requirement for certain classes of software-intensive 
				systems is the ability to self-adapt their structure and behavior at run-time when reacting to 
				changes that may occur to the system, its environment, or its goals. A major challenge 
				related to self-adaptive software systems is the ability to provide assurances of their 
				resilience when facing changes. Since in these systems, the components that act as 
				controllers of a target system incorporate highly complex software, there is the need to ...
			</description>

			<citationInformation>

				<totalCitations>1</totalCitations>
				
				<citation format="Chicago" year="2015">
					Quinn, Heather, Zachary Baker, Tom Fairbanks, Justin L. Tripp, and George Duran. "Software Resilience and the Effectiveness of Software Mitigation in Microcontrollers." Nuclear Science, IEEE Transactions on 62, no. 6 (2015): 2532-2538.
				</citation>
				<citation format="Chicago" year="">
					Wu, Yiqi, Fazhi He, Dejun Zhang, and Xiaoxia Li. "Service-Oriented Feature-Based Data Exchange for Cloud-Based Design and Manufacturing."
				</citation>


			</citationInformation>
			
		</publication>

		<publication>
			<title>Understanding Interoperability Issues of Web Service Frameworks</title>
			<author>Ivano Alessandro Elia</author>
			<author>Nuno Laranjeiro</author>
			<author>Marco Vieira</author>
			<date>2014/6/23</date>
			<additionalInformation>
				Conference: Dependable Systems and Networks (DSN), 2014 44th Annual IEEE/IFIP International Conference on
				Pages: 323-330
			</additionalInformation>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<description>
				Abstract—Web Services are a set of technologies designed to support the invocation of  
				remote services by client applications, with the key goal of providing interoperable 
				application-to-application interaction while supporting vendor and platform independence. 
				The goal of this work is to study the real level of interoperability provided by these 
				technologies through a massive experimental campaign involving a wide set of very popular 
				frameworks for web services, implemented using seven different programming languages. ...
			</description>			
			<citationInformation>

				<totalCitations>3</totalCitations>
			
				<citation format="Chicago" year="2015">
					Elia, Ivano Alessandro, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "A Practical Approach Towards Automatic Testing of Web Services Interoperability." International Journal of Web Services Research (IJWSR) 12, no. 3 (2015): 78-103.
				</citation>

				<citation format="Chicago" year="2014">
					Elia, Ivano Alessandro, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "A Field Perspective on the Interoperability of Web Services." In Services Computing (SCC), 2014 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 75-82. IEEE, 2014.
				</citation>						

				<citation format="Chicago" year="2014">
					Elia, Ivano Alessandro, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "ITWS: An Extensible Tool for Interoperability Testing of Web Services." In Web Services (ICWS), 2014 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 409-416. IEEE, 2014.
				</citation>

			</citationInformation>
		</publication>


	</publications>
</researcher>